<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Features on Hilbish</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/</link><description>Recent content in Features on Hilbish</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notification</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/notifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/notifications/</guid><description>Hilbish features a simple notification system which can be used by other plugins and parts of the shell to notify the user of various actions. This is used via the hilbish.message interface.
A message is defined as a table with the following properties:
icon: A unicode/emoji icon for the notification. title: The title of the message text: Message text/body channel: The source of the message. This should be a unique and easily readable text identifier.</description></item><item><title>Options</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/opts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/opts/</guid><description>Opts are simple toggle or value options a user can set in Hilbish. As toggles, there are things like autocd or history saving. As values, there is the motd which the user can either change to a custom string or disable.
Opts are accessed from the hilbish.opts table. Here they can either be read or modified
autocd Value: boolean Default: false The autocd opt makes it so that lone directories attempted to be executed are instead set as the shell&amp;rsquo;s directory.</description></item><item><title>Runner Mode</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/runner-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/versions/multiline-newline-fix/docs/features/runner-mode/</guid><description>Hilbish allows you to change how interactive text can be interpreted. This is mainly due to the fact that the default method Hilbish uses is that it runs Lua first and then falls back to shell script.
In some cases, someone might want to switch to just shell script to avoid it while interactive but still have a Lua config, or go full Lua to use Hilbish as a REPL. This also allows users to add alternative languages like Fennel as the interactive script runner.</description></item></channel></rss>