<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hilbish</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/</link><description>Recent content on Hilbish</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/docs/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/docs/faq/</guid><description>Is Hilbish POSIX compliant? No, it is not. POSIX compliance is a non-goal. Perhaps in the future, someone would be able to write a native plugin to support shell scripting (which would be against it&amp;rsquo;s main goal, but &amp;hellip;.)
Windows Support? It compiles for Windows (CI ensures it does), but otherwise it is not directly supported. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to improve this situation, checkout the discussion .
Where is the API documentation?</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/docs/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/docs/getting-started/</guid><description>To start Hilbish, open a terminal. If Hilbish has been installed and is not the default shell, you can simply run hilbish to start it. This will launch a normal interactive session. To exit, you can either run the exit command or hit Ctrl+D.
Setting as Default Login shell There are a few ways to make Hilbish your default shell. A simple way is to make it your user/login shell.</description></item><item><title>Install</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/install/</guid><description>Official Binaries The best way to get Hilbish is to get a build directly from GitHub. At any time, there are 2 versions of Hilbish recommended for download: the latest stable release, and development builds from the master branch.
You can download both at any time, but note that the development builds may have breaking changes.
For the latest stable release, check here: https://github.com/Rosettea/Hilbish/releases/latest For a development build: https://nightly.link/Rosettea/Hilbish/workflows/build/master Package Repositories Arch Linux (AUR) Hilbish is on the AUR.</description></item><item><title>Runner Mode</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/docs/features/runner-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/docs/features/runner-mode/</guid><description>Hilbish is unique, when interactive it first attempts to run input as Lua and then tries shell script. But if you&amp;rsquo;re normal, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really be using Hilbish anyway but you&amp;rsquo;d also not want this (or maybe want Lua only in some cases.)
The &amp;ldquo;runner mode&amp;rdquo; of Hilbish is customizable via hilbish.runnerMode, which determines how Hilbish will run user input. By default, this is set to hybrid which is the previously mentioned behaviour of running Lua first then going to shell script.</description></item></channel></rss>