<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Hilbish</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Hilbish</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:13:50 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>v2.2 Release</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.2-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 23:56:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.2-release/</guid><description>The release with full changelogs and prebuilt binaries can be seen at the v2.2.0 tag.
Welcome to a very long awaited release of Hilbish, and on Christmas. Just think of it as a long preparing, late Christmas gift. :) This release does not contain a whole lot of changes, but it is a new release with enhancements and bug fixes!
Documentation As is a trend, the documentation has been improved by ONE HUNDRED TIMES.</description></item><item><title>Improving Hilbish's Branding</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/improving-this-website/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 22:15:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/improving-this-website/</guid><description>Happy birthday Hilbish! As of last month, Hilbish is now 2 years old. Unfortunately I missed the official date, but I will still make a more focused post on the date (19st).
I decided to fix up this website and Hilbish&amp;rsquo;s logo, so that can be thought of as something for the 2 years milestone?
Logo Hilbish&amp;rsquo;s old logo was.. not that good. It definitely functioned as a logo, but the yellow part of it looked ugly (sorry old logo).</description></item><item><title>v2.1.2 Release</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.1.2-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:27:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.1.2-release/</guid><description>The release with full changelogs and prebuilt binaries can be seen at the v2.1.2 tag.
This release reverts the April Fool&amp;rsquo;s code additions in v2.1.1. It is functionally equal to v2.1.0. Nice!
A real release will come possibly in a few days or next week, so stay tuned for the good and feature-filled release of v2.2!</description></item><item><title>v2.1.1 Release</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.1.1-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 18:15:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.1.1-release/</guid><description>The release with full changelogs and prebuilt binaries can be seen at the v2.1.1 tag.
Welcome to a fresh new release of Hilbish! Some people (or none) may be awaiting the long coming v2.2 release with lots of features, but I needed to push out this little bug fix (wink) release.
Bug Fixes Validation checks for command input When running this version, you may have noticed an odd message that sometimes comes up when running commands.</description></item><item><title>v2.1 Release</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.1-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 18:25:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.1-release/</guid><description>The release with full changelogs and prebuilt binaries can be seen at the v2.1.0 tag.
Oh look! A new release of Hilbish! This time is the v2.1 release, with a small amount of features and mainly documentation changes and bug fixes.
Documentation There have been a few documentation enhancements for this release. This includes:
Adding the return types for all functions that need them Documenting Hilbish types like job objects and timers properly.</description></item><item><title>Hilbish v2.0 Release</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.0-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 01:55:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/v2.0-release/</guid><description>Hilbish v2.0 has been released! Well actually, it was released a week ago, but I only wrote this Hilbish blog after that.
This is a big release, coming 9 months after the previous v1.2.0 and featuring over 40+ bug fixes and tons of new features and enhancements, so let&amp;rsquo;s see what is in this release.
Documentation When querying about the problems people have with Hilbish, one of the issues was its poor documentation.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Hilbish blog</title><link>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosettea.github.io/Hilbish/blog/welcome/</guid><description>Hello! Welcome to the Hilbish blog. This will mainly contain release announcements and some other things relating to Hilbish (development).</description></item></channel></rss>